

ABOUT ME

Hello! With three years of experience, I am skilled in Python and Django as a Data Engineer and Backend Developer.

My skillset includes **self-education**, **critical thinking**, and the ability to lead small teams.

My greatest enthusiasm lies in the realm of game development and continually expanding my knowledge

CONTACT

- +52 984 280 0369
- famvazpom@gmail.com
- (C) Famvazpom
- famvazpom.tech
- Playa del Carmen, Mexico

LANGUAGES

- Spanish
- English

SKILLS

- Main Programming
 Languages: Python, C++/C#.
- BackEnd Frameworks:
 Django
- **Deep Learning**: TensorFlow, Keras.
- Machine Learning: Scikit-Learn, OpenCv
- Web Development:
 HTML,CSS, Javascript
- Front End Frameworks: React (Basic), Flutter.
- Main Cloud Providers: Azure, AWS.
- Data Analysis: Pandas
- SQL: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Maria DB, MS SQL Server.

Noe Vazquez Pompa

PYTHON DEVELOPER AND DATA ENGINEER

WORK HISTORY

Engineer Asistant (January 2020 - Now)

AV Electronic Services

- **Gym management system:** Design, development, deployment and maintenance of Web system using Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and MySQL for Membership fee collection for users from various gyms, reporting and tracking equipment failures within the establishment, management of staff, and administrative reporting.
- Server Deployment: Deployment of system instances for clients using cloud technologies such as Azure, AWS and PythonAnywhere.
- POS Application Development: Design, development and deployment of POS App using Django and MySql for sales management, inventory control, pricing, sales reports, and commission tracking.
- Repair and Maintenance of Electronic Equipment.

Project Leader and Main Developer (May 2022 - January 2023)

Riviera Movil

- Store and repair control system: Design, development, and deployment of Web App using Django, Django Rest Framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PostgreSQL for service order tracking, spare parts management, sales reports, commissions, and user administration.
- System Instance Deployment: Deployment of system instances for customers who purchase a license using MySQL and cloud technologies such as Azure, Amazon, and PythonAnywhere.
- License Management: Management of payment dates and servers of customer licenses.
- Technical Support

Project Leader and Main Developer (January 2021-June 2022)

Playacel Servicios Integrales

- Repair workshop control system development: Design, development, and deployment of a
 point-of-sale application using Django, Django Rest Framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 MySQL and Apache for service order tracking, sales reports, commissions, and user
 administration across 8 different branches within a single system.
- Technical Support
- Computer Mainentance: Create OS images, maintenance and computer restoration for branches.

PROJECTS - LINK TO MY PORTFOLIO (HERE)

Riviera Soft

Administrative system for service workshop control with integrated POS.

- Developed using Django, Django Rest Framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL/PostgreSQL and cloud technologies such as Azure and AWS.
- Used by 4 companies in Playa del Carmen, 2 in Cancún and 2 in Mexico City.

MATH-IAS - El tutor virtual para los estudiantes de la Universidad del Caribe

Implements a virtual math tutor on a web platform using Django, Django Rest Framework, React, Azure Web Apps, IBM Watson, and the Bayesian Knowledge Tracing (BKT) technique.

Aiming at monitoring the student learning progress using multiple levels of difficulty in which the student will need to progress to enhance their skills in different subjects implemented in the tutor also creating a LaTeX to Speech translate to implement voice explanations on different exercises.

CERTIFICATIONS

- AZ-900, Azure Fundamentals (July 2022)
- Many DataCamp certifications on ETL process, Data Cleaning, Supervised Learning and Data Visualization in Python and R.

EDUCATION

Universidad del Caribe (August 2016 - December 2023)

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Mayor in Data Engineering and Organizational Intelligence

- Studies in: Data Science, Data Engineering, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence.
- Relevant topics: Image Processing, Computer Vision, Data Mining, Statistics, Text Mining, Software Engineering, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence.
- Relevant Projects:
 - ALLMias Unicaribe (Spanish): Project where we use the MIAS database to train
 two models: one for classifying images submitted via the API, determining if an
 image is a mammogram or not using Google's teachable machine, and another
 model aiming to predict the presence of breast cancer using the Adaboost
 classifier. Additionally, an API and a web platform were created using Django REST
 Framework and React.
 - Topic Modeling Project (Spanish): Project where we use LDA to find the most common topics on multiple documents using NLTK and Scikit-Learn.
 - <u>Eigenfaces Project (Spanish)</u>: Project where we use PCA to create low dimensional images and recreating the original image using multiple projections and main components of the image.
 - TUUM Game Demo (Spanish): Project where we use the Unity game engine to create an interactive vocational test, with the goal of allowing students to take these questionnaires in a more engaging and user-friendly manner, catering to the preferences of the newer generations, you can play the demo here